/*
Title 	Gems.txt
Description 	by Nefarius
Sent by 	
name: This is a reference field, so that you know what gem or tune this line refers to.

letter: This field controls what string the game will use for the rune-letter displayed when the rune has been socketed into an item.

transform: This field controls what color the item the gem or rune has been socketed into is going to shift to, a list of colors can be found in Colors.txt (count starting from 0).

code: What item will these modifiers be appended to, this is what actually appends the stats to a gem, prior to 1.07 this was hardcoded and thus it was impossible to add new gems without editing the dlls.

nummods: This is another reference field, to make it easier to see how many different modifiers the gem or rune will have.

weaponMod1 to weaponMod3: An ID pointer to a property in Properties.txt, these columns control each of the three modifiers a gem will give to items using GemApplyType 0 (by default this is used by weapons).

weaponMod1Param to weaponMod3Param: The parameter passed on to the associated property, this is used to pass skill IDs, state IDs, monster IDs, montype IDs and the like on to the properties that require them. WARNING: You should not use properties that 
require parameters in this text file, since the parameters will stack when more then one gem of this type is socketed into the item, producing many undesired effects.

weaponMod1Min to weaponMod3Min: Minimum value to assign to the associated property. WARNING: Gem stats are not saved, thus having minimum and maximum assign different values will cause the gem stats to re-randomize every frame, until the gem is socketed 
into an item.

weaponMod1Max to weaponMod3Max: Maximum value to assign to the associated property. WARNING: Gem stats are not saved, thus having minimum and maximum assign different values will cause the gem stats to re-randomize every frame, until the gem is socketed 
into an item.

helmMod1 to helmMod3: An ID pointer to a property in Properties.txt, these columns control each of the three modifiers a gem will give to items using GemApplyType 1 (by default this is used by body armors and helmets).

helmMod1Param to helmMod3Param: The parameter passed on to the associated property, this is used to pass skill IDs, state IDs, monster IDs, montype IDs and the like on to the properties that require them. WARNING: You should not use properties that 
require parameters in this text file, since the parameters will stack when more then one gem of this type is socketed into the item, producing many undesired effects.

helmMod1Min to helmMod3Min: Minimum value to assign to the associated property. WARNING: Gem stats are not saved, thus having minimum and maximum assign different values will cause the gem stats to re-randomize every frame, until the gem is socketed 
into an item.

helmMod1Max to helmMod3Max: Maximum value to assign to the associated property. WARNING: Gem stats are not saved, thus having minimum and maximum assign different values will cause the gem stats to re-randomize every frame, until the gem is socketed 
into an item.

shieldMod1 to shieldMod3: An ID pointer to a property in Properties.txt, these columns control each of the three modifiers a gem will give to items using GemApplyType 2 (by default this is used by shields).

shieldMod1Param to shieldMod3Param: The parameter passed on to the associated property, this is used to pass skill IDs, state IDs, monster IDs, montype IDs and the like on to the properties that require them. WARNING: You should not use properties that 
require parameters in this text file, since the parameters will stack when more then one gem of this type is socketed into the item, producing many undesired effects.

shieldMod1Min to shieldMod3Min: Minimum value to assign to the associated property. WARNING: Gem stats are not saved, thus having minimum and maximum assign different values will cause the gem stats to re-randomize every frame, until the gem is socketed 
into an item.

shieldMod1Max to shieldMod3Max: Maximum value to assign to the associated property. WARNING: Gem stats are not saved, thus having minimum and maximum assign different values will cause the gem stats to re-randomize every frame, until the gem is socketed 
into an item.

*/

/*
文件名解析：
Gem(s)：宝石，在这里指除珠宝外的所有镶嵌物。
所以此文件就是描述除珠宝外所有镶嵌物，也就是嵌入到不同类别的装备上有不同属性的镶嵌物的地方。
此文件中的每一行表示一种宝石或符文。

name：此镶嵌物的名字。

letter：符文名。

transform：当此镶嵌物被镶入某装备时，对装备颜色的改变。与Colors.txt关联。

code：此镶嵌物的代码。

nummods：没搞明白是什么意思，请指教。

WeaponMod1Code：镶在武器上的属性1。

WeaponMod1Param：镶在武器上的属性1的参数。

WeaponMod1Min：镶在武器上的属性1的最小值参数。

WeaponMod1Max：镶在武器上的属性1的最大值参数。

WeaponMod2-3XXX：同是镶在武器上的属性，含义参考上面4列。

HelmMod1-3XXX：镶在头盔上的属性，含义参考前面的解释。

ShieldMod1-3XXX：镶在盾牌上的属性，含义参考前面的解释。

*eol：行尾标志，必须为0。

特殊说明：衣服跟头盔永远是一样的属性，所以在此并没有单独说明。
*/