/*
struct D2LevelDefBin
{
   DWORD dwQuestFlag;               //0x00
   DWORD dwQuestFlagEx;            //0x04
   DWORD dwLayer;                  //0x08
   DWORD dwSizeX;                  //0x0C
   DWORD dwSizeX_N;               //0x10
   DWORD dwSizeX_H;               //0x14
   DWORD dwSizeY;                  //0x18
   DWORD dwSizeY_N;               //0x1C
   DWORD dwSizeY_H;               //0x20
   DWORD dwOffsetX;               //0x24
   DWORD dwOffsetY;               //0x28
   DWORD dwDepend;                  //0x2C
   DWORD dwDrlgType;               //0x30
   DWORD dwLevelType;               //0x34
   DWORD dwSubType;               //0x38
   DWORD dwSubTheme;               //0x3C
   DWORD dwSubWaypoint;            //0x40
   DWORD dwSubShrine;               //0x44
   DWORD dwVis0;                  //0x48
   DWORD dwVis1;                  //0x4C
   DWORD dwVis2;                  //0x50
   DWORD dwVis3;                  //0x54
   DWORD dwVis4;                  //0x58
   DWORD dwVis5;                  //0x5C
   DWORD dwVis6;                  //0x60
   DWORD dwVis7;                  //0x64
   DWORD dwWarp0;                  //0x68
   DWORD dwWarp1;                  //0x6C
   DWORD dwWarp2;                  //0x70
   DWORD dwWarp3;                  //0x74
   DWORD dwWarp4;                  //0x78
   DWORD dwWarp5;                  //0x7C
   DWORD dwWarp6;                  //0x80
   DWORD dwWarp7;                  //0x84
   BYTE nIntensity;               //0x88
   BYTE nRed;                     //0x89
   BYTE nGreen;                  //0x8A
   BYTE nBlue;                     //0x8B
   DWORD dwPortal;                  //0x8C
   DWORD dwPosition;               //0x90
   DWORD dwSaveMonsters;            //0x94
   DWORD dwLOSDraw;               //0x98
};
*/

/*
Title 	Levels.txt File Guide
Description 	by Nefarius & Kingpin
Sent by 	
OVERVIEW:

This is the file that controls how the game link levels, what monsters and object that are spawned that are placed on the level.

RELATED .TXT FILES:

This file is using:

    Lvlmaze.txt
    LvlPrest.txt
    LvlSub.txt
    LvlTypes.txt
    monstats.txt
    AutoMap.txt
    LvlWarp.txt
    objgroup.txt



COLUMN DESCRIPTIONS :

Name 	This column has no function, it only serves as a comment field to make it easier to identify the Level name
Id 	Level ID (used in columns like VIS0-7)
Pal 	Palette (Color Palette loaded for the Level, you can change this but mostly the colors get messed up greatly)
Act 	The Act the Level is located in (internal numbering 0-4)
QuestFlag 	Used in Classic game only, sets a questflag. If this flag is set, a character must have completed the quest associated with the flag to take a town portal to the area in question. A character can always use a portal to get back to town.
QuestFlagEx 	Used in Expansion only, set a questflag. If this flag is set, a character must have completed the quest associated with the flag to take a town portal to the area in question. A character can always use a portal to get back to town.
Layer 	Each layer is an unique ID. This number is used to store each automap individual on a character. This is used by the game to remember what level the automap are for. (You need to use the extended levels plugin to be able to add additional layers)
SizeX 	sizeX in Normal. If this isn't a preset area this sets the X size for the area. Othervise use the same value here that are used in lvlprest.txt to set the size for the .ds1 file.

SizeY 	sizey in Normal. If this isn't a preset area this sets the Y size for the area. Othervise use the same value here that are used in lvlprest.txt to set the size for the .ds1 file.

nSizeX(N) 	sizeX in Nightmare. sizeX in Normal. If this isn't a preset area this sets the X size for the area. Otherwise use the same value here that are used in lvlprest.txt to set the size for the .ds1 file.

SizeY(N) 	sizey in Nightmare. If this isn't a preset area this sets the Y size for the area. Othervise use the same value here that are used in lvlprest.txt to set the size for the .ds1 file.

SizeX(H) 	sizeX in Hell. sizeX in Normal. If this isn't a preset area this sets the X size for the area. Othervise use the same value here that are used in lvlprest.txt to set the size for the .ds1 file.

SizeY(H) 	sizeX in Hell. If this isn't a preset area this sets the Y size for the area. Othervise use the same value here that are used in lvlprest.txt to set the size for the .ds1 file.

OffsetX 	This set the the X position in the world space

OffsetY 	This set the Y position in the world space

Depend 	This set what level_id are the Depended level. This is used by as example Monastery to place the entrance always at same location.
Teleport 	Controls if teleport is allowed in that level.

0 = Teleport not allowed
1 = Teleport allowed
2 = Teleport allowed, but not able to use teleport throu walls/objects (maybe for objects this is controlled by IsDoor column in objects.txt)
Rain 	Does it Rain/Snow in this Level (1=yes, 0=no), snow works only in act5.
Mud 	Unused setting (In pre beta D2 blizzard planed Rain to cause Mud which would have slowed your char's speed down, but this never made it into the final game), the field is read by the code but the return value is never utilized.
NoPer 	Setting for 3D Enhanced D2 that disables Perspective Mode for a specific level. (1=disabled, 0=enabled)
LOSDraw 	Allows you to look thru objects and walls even if they are not in a wilderness level. (1=yes, 0=no).
FloorFilter 	Probably has to do with Tiles and their Placement (function currently unknown) (1=yes, 0=no).

BlankScreen 	Probably has to do with Tiles and their Placement (function currently unknown) (1=yes, 0=no).

DrawEdges 	for levels bordered with mountains, walls (act 1 wildernesses for example) (1=yes, 0=no).
IsInside 	Is this level a Outdoor or Indoor area (1=yes, 0=no). Indoor areas are not effected by day-night cycles (they always use the same lighting-settings), this field also controls whenever sounds will echo if you're running the game with a sound 
card capable of it and have enviroment sound effects set to true
DrlgType 	Setting for Level Generation: 1=Random Maze, amount of rooms defined by LVLMAZE.TXT (the total size of all the rooms may not exceed the worldspace allocated to the area however), 2=pre set map (example: catacombs lvl4) and 3=Random Area with 
preset size (wildernesses).

LevelType 	The type of the Level (Id from lvltypes.txt)
Sub Columns 	IDs from LVLSub.txt, LVLSub.txt is used to randomize outdoor areas, such as spawning ponds in the blood moor and more stones in the Stoney Field, this is all changeable, the other subcolumns are explained in this post

SubType 	Setting Regarding Level Type (6=wilderness, 9=desert etc, -1=no subtype).

SubTheme 	Tells what subtheme an wilderness area should use. There are themes between 0-4, -1 use no subetheme.

SubWaypoint 	Setting Regarding Waypoints (does not control waypoint placement).

SubShrine 	Setting Regarding Shrines (does not control what shrines appear).
Vis0-7 	This controls what Level_ID the level are connected to on Server Side. What vis you use depend of what special tile your entrance are using. Normally cave levels are only using vis0-3 and wilderness areas 4-7

Warp0-7 	This controls the visual graphics then you move the mouse pointer over an entrance. To show the graphics you use an ID from lvlwarp.txt and the behavior on the graphics is controlled by lvlwarp.txt. You use same WarpX as you use VisX (ie if you 
use Vis0 for your level then you would use Warp0 to show the graphics).
Intensity 	Light Intensity: 0-255.

Red 	Red Lighting Strength (This works in 2D mode also)

Green 	Green Light Strengh (This works in 2D mode also)

Blue 	Blue Light Strength (This works in 2D mode also)
Portal 	This field is required for some levels, entering those levels when portal field isn't set will often crash the game. This also applies to duplicates of those levels created with both of the extended level plugins.
Position 	This controls if you can re-position a portal in a level or not.

1 = You can re-position the portal (it will use either map entry#76 or Tp Location #79. If both are set in same level it will use Tp Location)

0 = don't use re-position.
SaveMonster 	Does the game save the state of the Monsters for the area (1=yes, 0=no) (towns are set to 0 so that NPCs get respawned and hence get new items when you leave town).
Quest 	What quest is this level related to. This is the quest_id (as example the first quest Den of Evil are set to 1, since its the first quest)
WarpDist 	This sets the minimum distance from a VisX or WarpX location that a monster, object or tile can be spawned at. (also applies to waypoints and some preset portals)
MonLvl1 	Area (Dungeon) Level on Normal (controls the item level of items that drop from chests etc).
MonLvl2 	Area (Dungeon) Level on Nightmare (controls the item level of items that drop from chests etc).
MonLvl3 	Area (Dungeon) Level on Hell (controls the item level of items that drop from chests etc)
MonLvl1Ex 	Area (Dungeon) Level on Normal in D2X (controls the item level of items that drop from chests etc).
MonLvl2Ex 	Area (Dungeon) Level on Nightmare in D2X (controls the item level of items that drop from chests etc). If no ratio is set to 0 (in monstats.txt) the monster level of every monster spawned in this level, except monsters with boss set to 1 will 
be set to this level
MonLvl3Ex 	Area (Dungeon) Level on Hell in D2X (controls the item level of items that drop from chests etc). If no ratio is set to 0 (in monstats.txt) the monster level of every monster spawned in this level, except monsters with boss set to 1 will be 
set to this level
MonDen 	This is a chance in 100000ths that a monster pack will spawn on a tile, the maximum chance the game allows is 10% (aka 10000) in v1.10+
MonDen(N) 	Monster Density Nightmare. This is a chance in 100000ths that a monster pack will spawn on a tile, the maximum chance the game allows is 10% (aka 10000) in v1.10+
MonDen(H) 	Monster Density Hell. This is a chance in 100000ths that a monster pack will spawn on a tile, the maximum chance the game allows is 10% (aka 10000) in v1.10+
MonUMin 	Minimum Unique and Champion Monsters Spawned in this Level. Whenever any spawn at all however is bound to MonDen
MonUMax 	Maximum Unique and Champion Monsters Spawned in this Level. Whenever any spawn at all however is bound to MonDen
MonWndr 	Boolean switch (0/1) that sets whether unactivated monsters are allowed to roam the area (ala Wilderness), or whether they must stand put until activated (ala Den of Evil). 0 = cannot roam, 1 = can roam. Can make things like in Diablo, where 
monsters won't roam until activated.
MonSpcWalk 	This setting is hardcoded to certain level Ids, like the River Of Flame, enabling it in other places can glitch up the game, so leave it alone. It is not known what exactly it does however.
NumMon 	Number of different Monster Types that will be present in this area, the maximum is 13. You can have up to 13 different monster types at a time in Nightmare and Hell difficulties, selected randomly from nmon1-nmon25. In Normal difficulty you can 
have up to 13 normal monster types selected randomly from mon1-mon25, and the same number of champion and unique types selected randomly from umon1-umon25.
mon1-mon25 	Normal only. Spawned species, use ID from MonStats.txt. Only the first ten columns appear in the unmodded file. In 1.10 final, beta 1.10s and v1.11+ you can add the missing mon11-mon25 columns.
rangedspawn 	Give preference to monsters set to ranged=1 in MonStats.txt on Nightmare and Hell difficulties when picking something to spawn. Exact way this is done is unknown though.
nmon1-nmon25 	Nightmare/Hell only. Spawned species, use ID from MonStats.txt. Only the first ten columns appear in the unmodded file. In 1.10 final, beta 1.10s and v1.11+ you can add the missing nmon11-nmon25 columns. Due to what appears to be a bug 
Champion/Unique species uses this column also in nightmare/hell.
umon1-umon25 	Normal only. Champion/Unique species, use ID from MonStats.txt. Only the first ten columns appear in the unmodded file. In 1.10 final, beta 1.10s and v1.11+ you can add the missing umon11-umon25 columns.
cmon11-4 	Critter Species 1-4. Use id from monstats2.txt and only monsters with critter column set to 1 can spawn here. critter column is also found in monstats2.txt. Critters are in reality only present clientside.
cpct1-cpct4 	Controls the %chance a critter is spawned.
camt1-camt4 	(unknown). These columns are bugged, the game overrides the contents of columns 3-4 with the value from column 1 when it compiles the bin files.
Themes 	Which Theme is used for this Area? (unknown function), this field is accessed by the code but it is not exactly known what it does.
SoundEnv 	Referes to a entry in SoundEnviron.txt (for the Levels Music)
Waypoint 	255=No way Point, other #'s Waypoint ID (you can switch waypoint destinations between areas this way, not between acts however so don't even bother to try)
LevelName 	String Code for the Display name of the Level
LevelWarp 	String Code for the Display name of a entrance to this Level
EntryFile 	Which *.DC6 Title Image is loaded when you enter this area, this file MUST exist, otherwise you will crash with an exception when you enter the level (for all levels below the expansion row, the files must be present in the expension folders)
ObjGrp0-7 	Use the ID of the ObjectGroup you want to Spawn in this Area (from ObjGroups.txt).
ObjPrb0-7 	Object Spawn Possibility: the Chance for this object to occur (if you use ObjGrp0 then set ObjPrb0 to a value below 100)
Beta 	Reference Only (can be used for comments)

*/

/*
Levels.txt文件引导。 

Name: 内部名称，修改无效；

Id: 地图的ID代码；

Pal: 当前地图所采用的配色板；

Act: 地图所在的位置（0至4为有效数值）；

QuestFlag:仅作用于原版的暗黑中，主要是在完成特定的任务后所获得的SET装备奖励，这里用来指定任务；

QuestFlagEx:仅作用于资料片（LOD），主要是在完成特定的任务后所获得的SET装备奖励，这里用来指定任务；

Layer: 游戏内部的“层”设定，用来设置角色在小地图上的显示位置；

SizeX: 在“普通”难度下地图的X轴长度（注意这个数值同lvlprest.txt文件的关联）；

SizeY: 在“普通”难度下地图的Y轴长度（注意这个数值同lvlprest.txt文件的关联）；

SizeX(N): 在“恶梦”难度下地图的X轴长度（注意这个数值同lvlprest.txt文件的关联）；

SizeY(N): 在“恶梦”难度下地图的Y轴长度（注意这个数值同lvlprest.txt文件的关联）；

SizeX(H): 在“地狱”难度下地图的X轴长度（注意这个数值同lvlprest.txt文件的关联）；

SizeY(H): 在“恶梦”难度下地图的Y轴长度（注意这个数值同lvlprest.txt文件的关联）；

OffsetX: 地图X轴可用参数；

OffsetY: 地图Y轴可用参数；

Depend: 对于一些不需要随机生成的地图使用这个参数（比如说：ACT4的城镇）；

Teleport: 无用参数，说明：更确切一点说是修改这里没有什么意义；

Rain: 这个地图里面是否下雨/下雪（1=有天气影响，0=无影响），说明：下雪只在ACT5出现； 

Mud: 无用参数，说明：其实在D2的设计阶段曾打算如下雨等天气中，会有泥土溅起的效果，但一直并未实施；

NoPer: 此地图是否强制使用3D显示（1=强制，0=不强制）；

LOSDraw: 是否直接可以看到房屋的内部而不需要进入（1=允许，0=不允许）； 

FloorFilter: 是否过滤房屋、树等外景（1=是，0=否），说明：主要是针对DT1文件； 

BlankScreen: 外景参数（1=是，0=否）；

DrawEdges: 是否显示墙等物品的边缘（1=是，0=否）；

IsInside: 此地图是位于不可见的位置（如地下，1=是，0=否）；

DrlgType: 地图的生成方式：1=随机的生成，房间等物品的数量由LVLMAZE.TXT文件定义，2=固定地图（如：ACT1的关底），3=随机生成，但地图大小不做改变；

LevelType: 地图的类型（同lvltypes.txt文件关联）；

Sub Columns: 同LVLSub.txt的相关列关联；

SubType: 地图的外观级别，比如说：6=野外，9=沙漠，等等，-1=无子类型； 

SubTheme: 地图的外观主题，一般采用0-4的数值，-1表示不使用外观主题； 

SubWaypoint: 设定路点的参数（并不真正控制路点的位置）；

SubShrine: 设定随即出现的神坛参数（非实质操作参数）；

Vis0: 地图1号的入口/出口；

Vis1: 地图2号的入口/出口；

Vis2: 地图3号的入口/出口；

Vis3: 地图4号的入口/出口；

Vis4: 地图5号的入口/出口；

Vis5: 地图6号的入口/出口；

Vis6: 地图7号的入口/出口；

Vis7: 地图8号的入口/出口；

Warp #: 同lvlwarp.txt关联；

Intensity: 亮度的敏感值（0-255）；

Red: 红光的敏感值；

Green: 绿光的敏感值；

Blue: 蓝光的敏感值；

Portal: 无用参数，说明：尽管外文资料说此行为无效参数，但我本人认为这一列是在调整传送门的类型（红门还是蓝门，ylycloak注）；

Position: 地图所出现的位置；

SaveMonster: 是否记录下地图上怪物的状态，（1=是，0=否，一般城镇中将此数值设置为0，因为需要调整角色出城后回来时进行交易的物品种类）；

Quest: 任务关联参数；

WarpDist: 调整怪物同地图上各类元素的距离；

MonLvl1: “普通”级别下物品从箱子中掉落的级别（原版）；

MonLvl2: “恶梦”级别下物品从箱子中掉落的级别（原版）；

MonLvl3: “地狱”级别下物品从箱子中掉落的级别（原版）；

MonLvl1Ex: “普通”级别下物品从箱子中掉落的级别（资料片）；

MonLvl2Ex: “恶梦”级别下物品从箱子中掉落的级别（资料片）；

MonLvl3Ex: “地狱”级别下物品从箱子中掉落的级别（资料片）；

MonDen: “普通”级别下，当前地图中怪物的密度，说明：此项数值能够大于10000，但建议不要超过3000，过大的数值会倒置游戏运行速度的降低；

MonDen(N): “恶梦”级别下，当前地图中怪物的密度，说明：此项数值能够大于10000，但建议不要超过3000，过大的数值会倒置游戏运行速度的降低； 

MonDen(H): “地狱”级别下，当前地图中怪物的密度，说明：此项数值能够大于10000，但建议不要超过3000，过大的数值会倒置游戏运行速度的降低；

MonUMin: 当前地图中独有怪物和超级怪物的最小数量；

MonUMax: 当前地图中独有怪物和超级怪物的最大数量；

MonWndr: 布尔类型的参数，用来确认是否存在需要特定的条件才能够激活特定的怪物（比如说DIABLO需要五个封印来激活）；

MonSpcWalk: 无用参数；

NumMon: 当前地图中所允许存在的怪物种类；

Mon1-Mon10: 同monstats.txt文件中的ID列对应，表示在“普通”级别下当前地图中出现的怪物的类型，可以拓展至Mon25；

rangedspawn: 无用参数；

nmon1-10: 同monstats.txt文件中的ID列对应，表示在“恶梦”和“地狱”级别下当前地图中出现的怪物的类型，可以拓展至Mon25；

umon1-10: 同monstats.txt文件中的ID列对应，表示在“普通”级别下当前地图中出现特定怪物和超级怪物的类型，可以拓展至Mon25；

cmon1-4: 杂物的设置（同monstats.txt和monstats2.txt文件关联）；

cpct1-cpct4: 同cmon1-4列关联，比如说：如果cmon1列的数值为1，那么cpct1列相应的就应该为30；

camt1-camt4: 无用参数；

Themes: 当前地图所采用的主题，（目前看来没有什么用，ylycloak注）；

SoundEnv: 进入当前地图时所采用的背景音乐；

Waypoint: 路点的位置，255=没有路点，其它数值代表路点的ID，（呵，想直接进入牛关？呵，改这里吧）；

LevelName: 地图名称（内部代码）；

LevelWarp: 当进入当前地图时所显示的名称（内部代码）；

EntryFile: 当前地图需要调用哪些背景文件（*.Dc6格式）；

ObjGrp0-7: 当前地图所采用的物件组（同ObjectGroups.txt关联）；

ObjPrb0-7: 所采用物件组出现的机率（比如说：如果你想使用ObjGrp0，那么你就必须把ObjPrb0的数值设置为不大于100）；

Beta: 注释。
*/

/*
文件名解析：
Level(s)：级别，在这里指地图。
此文件是描述游戏中所有地图的文件。
此文件中的每一行表示一张地图。

每列的含义如下：

Name：当前地图的代码。

Id：当前地图的编号。

Pal：当前地图所采用的配色板。

Act：地图所在的位置，即在第几幕。0至4分别表示第1到5幕。

QuestFlag：当前地图是否对应于某任务。用于非资料片。

QuestFlagEx：当前地图是否对应于某任务。用于资料片。

Layer：游戏内部的“层”设定。

SizeX：当前地图在普通难度下的宽度，与LvlPrest.txt关联。

SizeY：当前地图在普通难度下的高度，与LvlPrest.txt关联。

SizeX(N)：当前地图在恶梦难度下的宽度，与LvlPrest.txt关联。

SizeY(N)：当前地图在恶梦难度下的高度，与LvlPrest.txt关联。

SizeX(H)：当前地图在地狱难度下的宽度，与LvlPrest.txt关联。

SizeY(H)：当前地图在地狱难度下的高度，与LvlPrest.txt关联。

OffsetX：当前地图的宽度偏移量。

OffsetY：当前地图的高度偏移量。

Depend：当前地图是否依附于其它地图。

Teleport：在当前地图瞬移是否有效果。

Rain：当前地图是否会下雨或下雪。

Mud：无用参数，相传是为制作泥土效果所留。

NoPer：当前地图是否使用3D模式显示，1表示始终使用。

LOSDraw：在当前地图是否可以在某房间外直接看到房间内部的东西，1表示可以。

FloorFilter：当前地图是否过滤房屋、树等外景，1代表是。

BlankScreen：当前地图是否含有外景。1代表是。

DrawEdges：当前地图是否显示边缘。1代表是。

IsInside：当前地图是否在外部不可见。1代表是。

DrlgType：当前地图的生成方式：1=随机的生成，房间等物品的数量由LVLMAZE.TXT文件定义，2=固定地图（如：ACT1的关底），3=随机生成，但地图大小不做改变。

LevelType：当前地图的类型（同lvltypes.txt文件关联）。

Sub Columns：同LVLSub.txt的相关列关联。

SubType：地图的外观级别，比如说：6=野外，9=沙漠，等等，-1=无子类型。

SubTheme：地图的外观主题，一般采用0-4的数值，-1表示不使用外观主题。

SubWaypoint：设定路点的参数（并不真正控制路点的位置）。

SubShrine：设定随即出现的神坛参数（非实质操作参数）。

 Vis0-7：地图0-7号的入口/出口。

Warp1-7：同lvlwarp.txt关联。

Intensity：亮度的敏感值（0-255）。

Red：红光的敏感值。

Green：绿光的敏感值。

Blue：蓝光的敏感值。

Portal：无用参数。

Position：地图所出现的位置。

SaveMonster：是否记录下地图上怪物的状态，（1=是，0=否，一般城镇中将此数值设置为0，因为需要调整角色出城后回来时进行交易的物品种类）。

Quest：任务关联参数。

WarpDist：调整怪物同地图上各类元素的距离。

MonLvl1：普通难度下此地图的级别（非资料片）。

MonLvl2：恶梦难度下此地图的级别（非资料片）。

MonLvl3：地狱难度下此地图的级别（非资料片）。

MonLvl1Ex：普通难度下此地图的级别（资料片）。

MonLvl2Ex：恶梦难度下此地图的级别（资料片）。

MonLvl3Ex：地狱难度下此地图的级别（资料片）。

MonDen：普通难度下当前地图中的怪物密度。

MonDen(N)：恶梦难度下当前地图中的怪物密度。

MonDen(H)：地狱难度下当前地图中的怪物密度。

MonUMin：普通难度下当前地图中金怪的最小数目。

MonUMax：普通难度下当前地图中金怪的最大数目。

MonUMin(N)：恶梦难度下当前地图中金怪的最小数目。

MonUMax(N)：恶梦难度下当前地图中金怪的最大数目。

MonUMin(H)：地狱难度下当前地图中金怪的最小数目。

MonUMax(H)：地狱难度下当前地图中金怪的最大数目。

MonWndr：当前地图中的怪物是否会游荡。

MonSpcWalk：无用参数。

NumMon：当前地图中所允许存在的怪物种类。

Mon1-Mon25：普通难度下当前地图中出现的怪物类型。与monstats.txt关联。

rangedspawn：无用参数。

nmon1-nmon25：恶梦难度下当前地图中出现的怪物类型。与monstats.txt关联。

umon1-umon25：地狱难度下当前地图中出现的怪物类型。与monstats.txt关联。

cmon1-4：地图上的杂物（如鸡，兔子之类）。与同monstats.txt和monstats2.txt文件关联。

cpct1-cpct4：cmon1-4的密度。

camt1-camt4：无用参数。

Themes：无用参数。

SoundEnv：进入当前地图时所采用的背景音乐。

Waypoint：传送小站在小站列表中的位置。255表示不在小站列表中。

LevelName：地图名称。

LevelWarp：当进入当前地图时所显示的名称。

EntryFile：当前地图需要调用哪些背景文件。

ObjGrp0-7：当前地图所采用的物件组。与ObjectGroups.txt关联。

ObjPrb0-7：所采用物件组出现的机率。

Beta：无用参数。

特殊说明：本文件大量引用了游戏小站中关于此文件的说明，感谢ylycloak等前辈们做的工作。
*/