/*
Title 	Sets.txt File Guide
Description 	by Alkalund, revised by Myhrginoc
Sent by 	
Refer to the Set Items File Guide for fields that define the attributes of specific items in a set.

index: string key linked to by the set field in SetItems.txt - used to tie all of the set's items to the same set.

name: string key to item's name in a .tbl file.

version: 0 = Available in Classic D2 and LoD Expansion; 100 = available in LoD Expansion only.

level: set level, perhaps intended as a minimum level for partial or full attributes to appear (reference only, not loaded into game).

GOLD ATTRIBUTES

PCode2a,PCode2b to PCode5a,PCode5b: An ID pointer of a property from Properties.txt, these columns control each of the five pairs of different partial set modifiers a set item can grant you at most.

PParam2a,PParam2b to PParam5a,PParam5b: The parameter passed on to the associated property, this is used to pass skill IDs, state IDs, monster IDs, montype IDs and the like on to the properties that require them, these fields support calculations.

PMin2a,PMin2b to PMin5a,PMin5b: Minimum value to assign to the associated property. Certain properties have special interpretations based on stat encoding (e.g. chance-to-cast and charged skills). See the File Guides for Properties.txt and ItemStatCost.
txt for further details.

PMax2a,PMax2b to PMax5a,PMax5b: Maximum value to assign to the associated property. Certain properties have special interpretations based on stat encoding (e.g. chance-to-cast and charged skills). See the File Guides for Properties.txt and ItemStatCost.
txt for further details.

FCode1 to FCode8: An ID pointer of a property from Properties.txt, these columns control each of the eight different full set modifiers a set item can grant you at most.

FParam1 to FParam8: The parameter passed on to the associated property, this is used to pass skill IDs, state IDs, monster IDs, montype IDs and the like on to the properties that require them, these fields support calculations.

FMin1 to FMin8: Minimum value to assign to the associated property. Certain properties have special interpretations based on stat encoding (e.g. chance-to-cast and charged skills). See the File Guides for Properties.txt and ItemStatCost.txt for further 
details.

FMax1 to FMax8: Maximum value to assign to the associated property. Certain properties have special interpretations based on stat encoding (e.g. chance-to-cast and charged skills). See the File Guides for Properties.txt and ItemStatCost.txt for further 
details.

*eol: terminator field, not used in game, primary purpose is to keep Microsoft Excel from misbehaving.

APPENDIX

Gold attributes will appear depending on how many set items are equipped, both partial set attributes (not all set items equipped) and full set attributes (all set items equipped only). If a set has X number of items, at most there will be X-1 partial 
attributes on any item.

PCode2a,PCode2b -> when any second set item is also equipped.
PCode3a,PCode3b -> when any third set item is also equipped.
PCode4a,PCode4b -> when any fourth set item is also equipped.
PCode5a,PCode5b -> when any fifth set item is also equipped.

*/

/*
index –物品名称索引；
name –绿色套装的名称；
version –物品出现的版本，0代表原版，100代表资料片；
level –套装的级别；
PCode2a –套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的附加第一级别魔法属性；
PParam2a -套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的魔法属性参数（第一级别）；
PMin2a -套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的魔法属性的最小值（第一级别）；
PMax2a -套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的魔法属性的最大值（第一级别）；
PCode2b -套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的附加第二级别魔法属性；
PParam2b -套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的魔法属性参数（第二级别）；
PMin2b -套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的魔法属性的最小值（第二级别）；
PMax2b -套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的魔法属性的最大值（第二级别）；
PCode3a -套装的物品拥有三套以上时所提供的附加第一级别魔法属性；
PParam3a -套装的物品拥有三套以上时所提供的魔法属性参数（第一级别）；
PMin3a -套装的物品拥有三套以上时所提供的魔法属性的最小值（第一级别）；
PMax3a -套装的物品拥有两套以上时所提供的魔法属性的最大值（第一级别）；
PCode3b -套装的物品拥有三套以上时所提供的附加第二级别魔法属性；
PParam3b -套装的物品拥有三套以上时所提供的魔法属性参数（第二级别）；
PMin3b -套装的物品拥有三套以上时所提供的魔法属性的最小值（第二级别）；
PMax3b -套装的物品拥有三套以上时所提供的魔法属性的最小值（第二级别）；

之后诸如：Pcode#a、Pparam#a、Pmin#a、Pmax#a、Pcode#b、Pparam#b、Pmin#b、Pmax#b等参见以上描述即可。


FCode1 – 全套装备集齐后的附加1号魔法属性；
FParam1 -全套装备集齐后的附加1号魔法参数；
FMin1 -全套装备集齐后的附加1号魔法属性的最小值；
FMax1 -全套装备集齐后的附加1号魔法属性的最大值；

之后诸如：Fcode#、Fparam#、Fmin#、Fmax#等参见以上描述即可。

*eol –文件结束标志。 

*/

/*
文件名解析：
Set(s)：套装。
所以此文件记录了游戏中所有套装。
文件中的每一行代表一个套装。


回复

    2楼
    2011-09-08 21:08

    举报 |

    zqtjingzi
    小吧主
    12

每列的含义如下：


回复

    3楼
    2011-09-08 21:08

    举报 |

    zqtjingzi
    小吧主
    12

Index：物品索引，也是此套装在游戏中的代码。

Name：名字，此套装在游戏中的名字。

Version：物品所能出现的最低版本。

Level：此套装的套装等级，也就是此套装中每件装备的物品等级。

PCode2a：属性2a的代码。所谓2a，就是指穿齐两件套装后获得的第一个属性。同理，2b是指穿齐两件套装后获得的第二个属性。3a是指穿齐三件套装后获得的第一个属性。

PParam2a：属性2a的参数。

PMin2a：属性2a的最小值参数。

PMax2a：属性2a的最大值参数。

以下2b、3a、3b、4a、4b、5a、5b各4列，含义类似。

FCode1-8：穿齐全部套装后的第1-8个属性的代码。

FParam1-8：穿齐全部套装后的第1-8个属性的参数。

FMin1-8：穿齐全部套装后的第1-8个属性的最小值参数。

FMax1-8：穿齐全部套装后的第1-8个属性的最大值参数。

Eol：行结束标志，必须填0。
*/