/*
state - the id pointer for this state, you would use this value in files such as skills.txt in those fields referring to states, for the state-property always use the id (line #)

id - for reference, this isn't compiled, the internal id corresponds always with the index in the txt file (ignoring the header and expansion lines).

group - you can group certain states together, this has the effect that they cannot stack (like the three cold armors of the sorceress). Beware as not all the code assigning states will care to check for this, if you use something exotic it will most 
likely produce glitches, if you stick to skills for state assignment it will work as intended.

remhit - whenever or not the state is dispelled when the unit takes a hit, due to the way this is coded it only applies to monsters, it wont be dispelled for players that get hit (not extensively tested, but code analysis sez so).

nosend - not yet analysed in detail

transform - whenever this state will transform the appearence of the unit (shape shift and holyshield).

aura - whenever or not this is an aura, aura states will not stack onscreen (ie the game cycles over active aura states), aura states are also dispelled when a monster is effected by conversion.

cureable - whenever or not an heal-enabled npc can remove this state (npcs automatically remove poisoning etc, hence those aren't checked) when you talk to them. (not verified)

curse - curse states cannot stack, the game will remove them when attempting to set a new state, it also controls whenever the duration of this state is reduced by the effects of the Cleansing aura and whenever curse resistance reduces it. Once a new 
curse state is applied the old one is removed.

active - whenever the state has a StateActiveFunc associated with it, StateActiveFuncs are actually the same as CltDoFuncs for skills. The active func is called every frame while the state is active.

immed - not yet analysed in detail.

restrict - whenever or not this state restricts skill usage (druid shapeshifts).

disguise - whenever this state make the game load another sprite for the unit (use in conjunction with transform).

blue - whenever this state applies a color change that overrides all others (such as from items).

attblue, dmgblue, armblue, rfblue, rlblue, rcblue, rpblue - these columns control whenever attack rating, damage, armor class, fire resistance, lightning resistance, cold resistance or poison resistance are displayed in blue color in the character stats 
screen.

stambarblue - whenever the stamina bar color is changed to blue (for stamina shrine). It does not control whenever you have infinite stamina (which you actually don't have, even with the shrine, it just gives you rediculous amounts of regen rate).

attred, dmgred, armred, rfred, rlred, rcred, rpred - these columns control whenever attack rating, damage, armor class, fire resistance, lightning resistance, cold resistance or poison resistance are displayed in red color in the character stats screen.

exp - when a unit effected by this state kills another unit, the summon owner will recieve experience (also when a unit with this state dies the summon owner also recieves experience, but not always due to some strange coding).

plrstaydeath, monstaydeath, bossstaydeath - whenever the state is removed when the unit dies (for players, monsters and special monsters). The last column will prevent bosses from shattering (from what I can tell).

hide - when the unit has died, the corpse and death anims will not be drawn.

shatter - whenever the unit shatters or explodes when it dies, this is heavily hardcoded, it will always use the ice shatter for all states other then STATE_UBERMINION.

udead - whenever this state prevents the corpse from being selected by spells and the ai.

life - when a state with this is active, it cancels out the native life regen of monsters. (using only the mod part instead of accr).

green - whenever this state applies a color change that overrides all others (such as from items). (see blue column, which seams to do the same).

pgsv - whenever this state is associated with progressive spells and will be looked up when the charges are triggered.

nooverlays - related to assigning overlays to the unit, not extensively researched yet.

noclear - like the previous column, also only used on states with the previous column enabled.

bossinv - whenever this state will use the minion owners inventory clientside (this is what makes the decoy always show up with your own equipment, even when you change what you wear after summoning one).

meleeonly - prevents druids that wield a bow or crossbow while shape shifted from firing missiles, and will rather attack in melee.

notondead - not researched yet

overlay1-4 - exact usage depends on the state and how the code accesses it, overlay1 however is the one you should generally be using.

pgoverlay - overlay shown on target of progressive skill when chargeup triggers.

castoverlay - overlay displayed when the state is applied initially (later replaced by overlay1 or whatever applicable by code).

removerlay - like castoverlay, just this one is displayed when the state expires.

stat - primary stat associated with the state, mostly used for display purposes (you should generally use skills.txt for assigning stats to states).

setfunc - clientside callback function invoked when the state is applied initially.

remfunc - clientside callback function invoked when the state expires or is otherwise removed.

missile - the missile that this state will utilize for certain events, how this is used depends entirely on the functions associated with the state.

skill - the skill that will be queried for this state in some sections of code, strangely enough this contradicts the fact states store their assigner skill anyway (via STAT_MODIFIERLIST_SKILL)

itemtype - what item type is effected by this states color change.

itemtrans - the color being applied to this item (only going to have an effect on alternate gfx, inventory gfx isn't effected).

colorpri - the color priority for this states color change, the, this can range from 0 to 255, the state with the highest color priority will always be used should more then one co-exist on the unit. If two states exist with the same priority the one 
with the lowest id is used (IIRC).

colorshift - index for the color shift palette picked from the *.PL2 files (see Paul Siramy's state color tool for info).

light-r, light-g, light-b - change the color of the light radius to what is indicated here, (only has an effect in D3D and glide of course).

onsound - sound played when the state is initially applied.

offsound - sound played when the state expires or is otherwise removed.

gfxtype - what unit type is used for the disguise gfx (1 being monsters, 2 being players, contratey to internal game logic).

gfxclass - the unit class used for disguise gfx, this corresponds with the index from monstats.txt and charstats.txt

cltevent - clientside event callback for this state (likely very inconsistent with the server side events, beware).

clteventfunc - callback function invoked when the client event triggers.

cltactivefunc - cltdofunc called every frame the state is active

srvactivefunc - srvdofunc called every frame the state is active

*/

/*
(A). state：状态名称；
(B). id：ID编号，可扩展；
(C). group：状态组。处在同一组的几个状态无法被同时激活；
(D). remhit：不明。仅有Cloak of Shadows为1(但性质很接近的InnerSight却也是空)；
(E). nosend：可能在服务器端和客户端传输数据时起作用。大多数为1的是被动技能，但是Bar的掌握系却是空；
(F). transform：是否是变形的状态；
(G). aura：状态是否以灵气方式作用；
(H). curable：该状态是否可以被治疗；
(I). curse：状态是否以诅咒方式作用；
(J). active：状态是否有个激活效果(?)；
(K). immed：状态是否立刻起作用；
(L). restrict：变形状态中是否限制使用技能；
(M). disguise：状态是否会改变图像效果。基本是和transform一起出现的，除了HolyShield；
(N). blue：该状态是否使被作用者变成蓝色，例如冰冻效果；
(O). attblue：该状态下命中率栏是否显示为蓝色；
(P). damblue：该状态下伤害力栏是否显示为蓝色；
(Q). armblue：该状态下防御力栏是否显示为蓝色；
(R). rfblue：该状态下火抗属性栏是否显示为蓝色；
(S). rlblue：该状态下电抗属性栏是否显示为蓝色；
(T). rcblue：该状态下冰抗属性栏是否显示为蓝色；
(U). stambarblue：该状态下体力栏是否显示为蓝色；
(V). rpblue：该状态下毒抗属性栏是否显示为蓝色；
(W). attred：该状态下命中率栏是否显示为红色；
(X). damred：该状态下伤害力栏是否显示为红色；
(Y). armred：该状态下防御力栏是否显示为红色；
(Z). rfred：该状态下火抗属性栏是否显示为红色；
(AA). rlred：该状态下电抗属性栏是否显示为红色；
(AB). rcred：该状态下冰抗属性栏是否显示为红色；
(AC). rpred：该状态下毒抗属性栏是否显示为红色；
(AD). exp：对转换系技能起作用。该列为1的时候，被转换的单位也会为你赚经验值；
(AE). plrstaydeath：与尸体有关。也许是当角色死亡时仍可以起作用的状态标识?
(AF). monstaydeath：与尸体有关。也许是对死亡的怪物/角色起作用的状态标识?
(AG). bossstaydeath：与尸体有关。
(AH). hide：隐藏起真正的图像? 除了Decoy和ShadowWarrior/Master外，都是"擦除"尸体的效果；
(AI). shatter：该状态是否使被作用者在死亡时被打碎；
(AJ). udead：该状态是否去除被作用者的尸体(或是无法选择被作用者尸体?)；
(AK). life：该状态是否影响生命值(或是影响生命值的自动恢复?)；
(AL). green：左下方的生命球是否变成绿色；
(AM). pgsv：该状态是否逐渐起作用的(不明白什么意思)；
(AN). nooverlays：没有Overlays?
(AO). noclear：仅有Bone Armor和Cyclone Armor为1；
(AP). bossinv：仅有Decoy为1；
(AQ). meleeonly：当状态激活时仅能使用近身攻击；
(AR). notondead：和尸体有关?
(AS～AV). overlay1～4：在Overlay.txt中的对应动画ID；
(AW). pgsvoverlay：当状态逐渐起作用时候的动画ID；
(AX). castoverlay：产生该状态时候的动画ID；
(AY). removerlay：状态结束时候的动画ID；
(AZ). stat：是否影响角色状态；
(BA). setfunc：状态激活时调用的函数；
(BB). remfunc：状态结束时调用的函数；
(BC). missile：状态激活时产生的Missile；
(BD). skill：触发状态时使用的技能；
(BE). itemtype：该状态可以影响的物品类型；
(BF). itemtrans：该状态引起的物品颜色变化；
(BG). colorpri：该状态引起的物品颜色变化强度(色深，估计是百分比)；
(BH). colorshift：颜色变化后的新颜色(?)；
(BI). light-r：状态引起光源变化的红光部分(或者仅仅是红色?)；
(BJ). light-g：状态引起光源变化的绿光部分(或者仅仅是绿色?)；
(BK). light-b：状态引起光源变化的蓝光部分(或者仅仅是蓝色?)；
(BL). onsound：状态开始时播放的声音；
(BM). offsound：状态结束时播放的声音；
(BN). gfxtype：当该状态的transform/disguise列为1的时候(变形的状态)，通过这里指定使用哪种图形：2－7个游戏角色；1－怪物(包括怪物/雇佣兵/NPC/背景人物等等)；
(BO). gfxclass：如果gfxtype=1，那么这里指定怪物ID(在monstats.txt里的hcidx)；如果gfxtype=2，通过这里指定角色ID：
0 = Amazon 亚马逊女战士
1 = Sorceress 女法师
2 = Necromancer 死灵巫师
3 = Paladin 圣骑士
4 = Barbarian 野蛮人
5 = Druid 德鲁伊
6 = Assassin 刺客
(BP). cltevent：在客户端触发状态的事件；
(BQ). clteventfunc：客户端调用的函数；
(BR). cltactivefunc：状态激活时客户端调用的函数；
(BS). srvactivefunc：状态激活时服务器端调用的函数；
(BT). eol：行结束标志，0。
*/