/*
Weapons.txt

This guide is based on Ric Faith 1.09x guide.

9/7 fileguide completed.
9/7. Added my discovery on how component column works.
9/7. Added explanation for alternativegfx column (thanx Paul) and it still works in 1.10

name: Reference only, its a comment field.

type: first base type (code from itemtypes.txt)

type2: second base type (code from itemtypes.txt)

code: is not needed to be added to string table anymore. This is a 3 letter/number code that need to be unique and
not used by other items.

alternategfx: This is the code of the DCC to use for a Player Animation.

For instance, the Gothic Shield (code=gts) has kit in its alternategfx column. That means that if a Barbarian equip himself whith that shield, in his A1 (Attack 1) mode animation his SH (Shield) layer component will use the DCC BASHKITA11HS.DCC, and NOT 
the file BASHGTSA11HS.DCC nor the file BASHBUCA11HS.DCC.

namestr: If namestr code is not added to a string table it will use that name in the field. If you want a string name with space you need to add it to your string table.

version: 0=Classic D2, 100=Expansion (A item set to 100 here cannot be generated in classic d2).

compactsave: 1=use compactsave 0=don't use compactsave. This is used to get a smaller filesize. This will not save
any stats to the item, this means it will not save any quantity, automagic, affixes, damage, armor, durability e.tc.
(This is used by items that don't need any stats stored like Healing potions, gems).

rarity: 0 = Exclude this item from armor rack, 1 and higher sets the rarity for this item to be droped from an armor rack.
(There need to be atleast one armor with rarity 1 othervise the game will crash when you use an armor rack).

spawnable: 1=can be sold by NPCs, 0=can never be sold by NPCs (even if you make them sell it thru the vendor columns)

mindam: Minimum one-handed damage the weapon can cause

maxdam: Maximum one-handed damage the weapon can cause

1or2handed: Boolean (1=yes,0=no) for whether weapon can be carried in 1 or 2 hands by Barbarian

2handed: 1 = this is a two handen weapon, 0 = this is a one handed weapon

2handmindam: Minimum two-handed damage the weapon cause

2handmaxdam: Maximum two-handed damage the weapon cause

minmisdam: Minimum ranged damage the weapon can cause

maxmisdam: Maximum ranged damage the weapon can cause

rangeadder: Adds additional range for melee weapon attacks (bare hand's range = 1)

speed: Possitive value = slower weapon speed, negative value = faster weapon speed. This speed value is of course then further modified by each classes individual weapon proficiencies

StrBonus: %age of Str taken into account for Bonus damage

DexBonus: %age of Dex taken into account for Bonus damage

reqstr: Required Strength 0-65535 (If you set a higher value than 65535 or less than 0 you will have a rollover)

reqdex: Required Dexterity 0-65535 (If you set a higher value than 65535 or less than 0 you will have a rollover)

durability: base durability (255 is maximum, higher value will make a rollover, so if you set Durability to 257 it will set it to durability 1 of 1)

nodurability: 1=indestructible, 0=use durability

level: base item level (aka a monster with a mlvl of 20 cannot drop a lvl30 armor for eg, used by the "armo#" preset TCs)

levelreq: the minimum level you need to have to use that item

cost: base cost

gamble cost: not used, reference only.

magic lvl: additional magic level when finding the item aka: If you gamble at lvl10 you can get lvl20 affixes if this is set to 10 for eg

auto prefix: Group # from automagic.txt (base affixes, like built in hp/resistances)

OpenBetaGfx: no use (reference to what alternategfx it was using in the d2 beta)

normcode: normal item code (it's used by game/cube upgrade code)

ubercode: exceptional item code (it's used by game/cube upgrade code)

ultracode: elite item code (it's used by game/cube upgrade code)

wclass: 1 handed weapon class, determines what style of attack to use (eg. 1hs, 1ht, hth)

2handedwclass: 2 handed weapon class, determines what style of attack to use

component: This tells what layer it should use from composit.txt to show the item on the character. (composit.txt are 16
lines that range from 0 (HD) to 15 (S8) and 16 means "no player animation").

hit class: what type of effects are displayed/heard when enemy is struck with weapon

invwidth: width in inventory cells

invheight: height in inventory cells

stackable: can this item be stacked 1=yes, 0=no

minstack: min ammount of quantity

maxstack: max ammount quantity

spawnstack: when randomly spawned, how many in a stack

flippyfile: flip gfx (dropping gfx)

invfile: inventory gfx

uniqueinvfile: unique inventory gfx

setinvfile: set inventory gfx

hasinv: 1 can be socketed, 0 cannot be socketed (You need to set MaxSock1/25/40 in itemtypes.txt to atleast 1 to have sockets in the item)

gemsockets: maximum number of sockets

gemapplytype: gem effecs 0=weapon, 1=armor/helm, 2=shield (If you add a higher value it wouldn't add the socket)

special: Not used, Comment field.

useable: 0=you cannot rightclick, 1=you can rightclick on this item

dropsound: tells what sound you use when the item is dropped. The name it uses is from Sound column in sounds.txt

dropsfxframe: Number of frames the sound will use.

usesound: tells what sound you use when the item is use. The name it uses is from Sound column in sounds.txt

unique: 1 = always unique, 0 = not always unique (This is used by questitems to have the item as always unique)

transparent: unknown function

transtbl: unknown function (But are always using 5)

quivered: is this item a stack of ammo 1=yes, 0=no

lightradius: Not used.

belt: numberic Id from belts.txt (defines number of potion slots)

quest: for quest items (quest ID)

questdiffcheck: sets in what difficulty this item is a questitem.

missiletype: missile to shoot if you throw this item (id from missiles.txt)

durwarning: the dur warning icon to display when the item is about to break

qntwarning: quantity warning icon to display if you wasted most of the stack

gemoffset: unknown

bitfield1: set to 1 for leather items, to 3 for metal ones.

Vendor Columns: (replace Vendor with the vendor name aka CharsiMin etc)

VendorsMin: minimum amount of items of this type the vendor can sell

VendorsMax: maximum amount of items of this type the vendor can sell

VendorsMagicMin: minimum amount of magic items of this type the vendor can sell

VendorsMagicMax: maximum amount of magic items of this type the vendor can sell

vendorsMagicLvl: Max magic level an item can get from the affixes.

Source Art: unknown

Game Art: unknown

Transform and invTrans : Index telling which colormap .dat to use for this item
(like 1=dataglobalitemspalettegrey.dat, 8=dataglobalitemspaletteinvgreybrown.dat).
This is telling what are the pixels that will change colors
(only transform brown pixels to dark green ? transform all pxiels to dark green ?).
For details, check http://d2mods.xfernet.com/colormaps.php
Transform is for the Animation of the player, while InvTrans is for the Inventory gfx

SkipName: for items like the viper amulet (which dosent say viper amulet two times) (skips the base name)

NightmareUpgrade: item code of the item the vendor will sell instead of this item on NM (xxx=no change)

HellUpgrade: item code of the item the vendor will sell instead of this item on HELL (xxx=no change)

nameable: 1=can be personalized, 0=cannot be personalized

PermStoreItem: Boolean will item always be sold by sellers? Item cannot be depleted


Annex A - Calculation of affixes available for item - by Ruvanal
This is from 1.09x (have no idea if anything here has been changed)

Terms
alvl = affix level. For an item this is the level that is used to compare to the level and max level as found in the prefix and suffix tables. When referring to a prefix/suffix it is the value listed in the level column.

ilvl = internal level (also referred to sometimes as the item level; better yet item creation level). This value is set at the time of an items creation. For monster drops the ilvl=mlvl. (BTW ilvl matches up with the terminology of the 1.07/1.08 cubemain
.txt---'itemlevel pct a')

mlvl = monster level.

clvl = character level.

qlvl = quality level. This value is found in the level column of armor.txt, weapons.txt and misc.txt. This is the value that is used to create the weapXX and armoXX treasure classes.
magic_lvl = magic level bonus on some items. Currently the only ones that have this are wands (normal and exceptional, but not the elite ones), staves, orbs (all with a value of 1) and circlets (circlet=3, Coronet=8, Tiara=13, Diadem=1.

When an item is generated that has affixes the alvl is calculated* from ilvl and qlvl as follows

If (ilvl>99) then {ilvl=99}
if (qlvl>ilvl) then {ilvl=qlvl} ;** see note below
if (magic_lvl>0) then {alvl=ilvl+magic_lvl}
else
{
if (ilvl<(99-qlvl/2))
then {alvl=ilvl-qlvl/2}
else {alvl=2*ilvl-99}
}
If (alvl>99) then {alvl=99}

*all calculations use integers so there are no fractions at any step.
** this new ilvl value is only used for the duration of this calculation. The ilvl value that is stored in the items data file will remain unchanged.

*/

/*
name: 物品的指导名字，注释用；

type:itemtypes.txt里的代码；

type2: itemtypes.txt里的代码；

code: 物品代码，不能重复；3个字母或数字；

alternategfx: 装备上后，角色的动画。比如，歌德盾牌这一列是KIT，野蛮人（BA）装备了这种盾牌
（SH）的普通攻击动画（A1）就是BASHKITA11HS.DCC。最后3个字母见WCLASS列；

namestr: 字符串键名；

version: 版本；

compactsave: 存档是否压缩（如果这个物品的属性只有一种，就不用记录它的属性了）；

rarity: 0 = 从装备架中剔除此类物品的任何信息；1或者更大的数字可以调整此类物品的掉宝率。说明：你至少应该拥有1个以上的此项数值不为零的装备，否则游戏就会出错而无法正常运行；

spawnable: 是否能够被NPC出售。说明：这里是能否被出售的关键设定，它高于其它位置（相关TXT文件）的设定。1=能够被NPC出售，0=无法出售；

mindam: 单手最小伤害；

maxdam: 单手最大伤害；

1or2handed: 决定野蛮人能否单手拿起一件双手武器；

2handed: 是否双手武器；

2handmindam: 双手最小伤害；

2handmaxdam: 双手最大伤害；

minmisdam: 远程最小伤害；

maxmisdam: 远程最大伤害；

rangeadder: 近战武器的攻击范围（空手是1）；

speed: 影响角色奔跑速度，越小，跑得越快；

StrBonus: 计算物理攻击力时，每100点力量加StrBonus%乘以武器的攻击力；

DexBonus: 计算物理攻击力时，每100点敏捷加DexBonus%乘以武器的攻击力；

reqstr: 力量需要（0-65535，超过65535将减去一次65535）；

reqdex: 敏捷需要（0-65535，超过65535将减去一次65535）；

durability: 耐久（0-255，超出的部分同上）；

nodurability: 为1时，不会损坏；

level: 等级；

levelreq: 等级需要；

cost:价格；

gamble cost:无用参数，仅作为参考；

magic lvl: 物品魔法属性需要的级别；

auto prefix: 成组的魔法前后缀，同automagic.txt文件关联；

OpenBetaGfx: 无用参数；

normcode/ubercode/ultracode: 物品对应的普通，扩展，精华物品代码，在升/降级时使用；

wclass/2handedwclass: 决定攻击动画所用DCC文件名的最后3个字母；

component: 角色使用此物品时，采用哪一层（Layer）；同composit.txt文件关联；

hit class: 敌人被击中时的声光效果；

invwidth: 宽；

invheight: 高；

stackable: 是否为一个整体（比如说“弓箭”）；1=是，0=不是；

minstack:作为整体的最小数目；

maxstack: 作为整体的最大数目；

spawnstack: 随机生成时的数目；

flippyfile: 掉出时的动画；

invfile: 在物品栏里所用的图象；

uniqueinvfile: 暗金物品在物品栏里所用的图象；

setinvfile: 套装物品在物品栏里所用的图象；

hasinv: 能否打孔；

gemsockets: 孔的最大数目；

gemapplytype: 宝石的效果：0武器，1甲胄和帽子，2盾牌；

special: 无用；

useable: 能否右键使用；

dropsound: 掉下时的音效；

dropsfxframe: 音效的帧数；

usesound: 使用时的音效；

unique: 是否总是暗金。任务物品专用；

transparent: 未知；

transtbl: 未知；

quivered: 是否弹药；

lightradius: 无用；

belt:同belts.txt中的数字ID（定义药水的放置数量）；

quest: 任务ID，任务物品用；

questdiffcheck: 是否任务物品；

missiletype: 投掷时用的投射物(missiles.txt里的ID) ；

durwarning: 投掷时，剩下多少时警告；

qntwarning: 投掷时，剩下多少时警告；

gemoffset: 未知；

bitfield1: 1，皮革制；3，金属制；

VendorsMin: NPC出售这件物品时的最小数量；

VendorsMax: NPC出售这件物品时的最大数量；

VendorsMagicMin: NPC出售这件物品时其所能包含的魔法属性的最少项；

VendorsMagicMax: NPC出售这件物品时其所能包含的魔法属性的最多项；

vendorsMagicLvl: 魔法类物品在出售时所能包含的最大的魔法前后缀级别。说明：同MagicPrefix.txt、MagicSuffix、AutoMagic三个文件关联；

Source Art: 无用参数；

Game Art: 无用参数；

Transform and invTrans: 索引，告诉程序使用哪一个整体动作；

SkipName: 是否跳过最初的名称，比如说：viper amulet；

NightmareUpgrade: 在“恶梦”难度下，此种物品的出售代码（xxx=无变化）；

HellUpgrade: 在“地狱”难度下，此种物品的出售代码（xxx=无变化）；

nameable: 是否能够被重命名（如ACT5中的Q3）；1=允许；0=不允许；

PermStoreItem: 物品是否总有出售。
*/

/*
mindam：单手最小伤害。

maxdam：单手最大伤害。

1or2handed：对于野蛮人来说能否用单手拿起这件双手武器。0表示不能，1表示能。

2handed：是否是双手武器。0表示不是，1表示是。

2handmindam：双手最小伤害。

2handmaxdam：双手最大伤害。

minmisdam：远程攻击时的最小伤害。

maxmisdam：远程攻击时的最大伤害。

rangeadder：近战武器的攻击范围（空手是1）；

reqdex：装备所需敏捷。

wclass：单手攻击时的动画。与WeaponClass.txt文件关联。

2handedwclass：双手攻击时的动画。与WeaponClass.txt文件关联。

hitclass：打击类别。

questDiffCheck：任务难度检查。即普通的吉得宝不能用来完成地狱的任务。

*/

struct D2WeaponClassTxt
{
   union
   {
      unsigned int dwCode; //0x00
      char szCode[4]; //0x00
   };
};